Finding Aid for Raymond A. Ruge Ice Yacht Technical Drawing Collection
Hudson River Maritime Museum
Raymond A. Ruge Ice Yacht Technical Drawings
1902 - 1974
Ice Yacht Technical Drawings designed by Raymond A. Ruge and E.A. Millenbach. Blueprints and tissue drawings from 1902 - 1974, primarily Hudson River Ice Yachts.
44 drawings in 3 roll boxes
Ruge, Raymond A.
Hudson River Maritime Museum 50 Rondout Landing Kingston, NY 12401
This collection is open to researchers, by appointment, without restriction.
Raymond A. Ruge, Ice Yacht Designer E.A. Millenbach, Designer of 1947 Renegade II Ice Yacht
technical drawings; Yachts--Design and construction
This collection contains 44 drawings in 3 roll boxes. Ice Yacht technical drawings by Raymond A. Ruge with six of 1947 Renegade II by E.A. Millenbach. Included are tissue, blueprint, construction details. Date range of 1902 - 1974 with majority in 1940s. Ice Yachts were used in the Hudson Valley, New York.
- Ice yacht plans. Jack Frost restoration., 1971 - 1974 (Box 1)
- Jack Frost colored blueprint showing sail plan for restoration. Drawn by Ray Ruge, 1971 - 1973 (Box 1)
- Sail plan of the new Jack Frost ice yacht., 1902 (Box 1)
- The Gryphon, actual drawing. Figurehead. (Box 1)
- Ice Yacht for Dr. T. F. MacDonald, Edmonton, Alberta. R.A. Ruge, Designer, 1943 (Box 2)
- Full size detail of Gooseneck. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company, Cohasset, MA. Raymond A. Ruge, Designer, Piermont, N.Y., 1945 (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Mead 50 Ice Yacht. Mead Gliders, Chicago, IL. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Marconi Sail for Baywing IV Chassis. Ice Yacht. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- 200 Square Foot Class Bow Steering Ice Yacht for Hudson Highlands Country Club. Raymond A. Ruge., 1936 (Box 2)
- Class C Bow Steering Ice Yacht. Raymond A. Ruge, Designer. Blueprint and tissue., 1939 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht.Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint, 1947 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht. Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint, 1947 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht. Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint, 1947 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht. Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint. Lines and Offsets, 1947 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht. Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint. Construction Details, 1947 (Box 2)
- Renegade II. Ice Yacht. Designed by E.A. Millenbach. Blueprint. Construction Details., 1947 (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Yankee Ice Yacht, Alcort Incorporated, Waterbury, CT. Blueprint. (Box 2)
- Ice Yacht. Sail plan. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company. Tissue., 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Hull and Sail plan. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company.Tissue, 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Blitzen. Tissue., 1938 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company. Steel Rudder Fork and Quadrant and Steel runner chock (fixed). (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht drawings. R.A. Ruge.Tissue., 1947 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Cast Iron Runner details. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company. Raymond A. Ruge, Designer., 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Minx IV. Sail plan. Hull plan. Tissue, 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Sail plan. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company.Tissue., 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company. Sail, mast plan.Tissue., 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht. Sketch designs. Racing Skeeter for Hagerty Company. Tissue., 1945 (Box 3)
- Ice Yacht for Dr. T.F. MacDonald, Edmonton, Alberta.Sail plan. Ray Ruge, designer., 1943 (Box 3)